<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<id>/</id>
	<title />
	<link rel="self" href="/" />
	<rights>2021</rights>
	<updated>2021-01-04T22:25:04Z</updated>
	<entry>
		<id>/posts/cloudcomputing</id>
		<title>What is Cloud Computing</title>
		<link href="/posts/cloudcomputing" />
		<updated>2021-01-05T02:19:58Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;h1 id="what-is-cloud-computing"&gt;What is cloud computing?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell cloud computing allows access to a large amount of computing power in a fully virtualized manner. The aim of this technology is to deliver computing as a utility.
Utility computing is a business model of on-demand delivery of computing power ( pay-as-you-go).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud computing provides multiple services initially offered by microsoft, google and amazon based on a model where computing infrastructure is viewed as a “cloud”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principle of cloud computing behind this model is to offer computing, storage and software as service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Dr. Rajkumar Buyya's Cyberhome says “Cloud is a parallel and distributed computing system consisting of a collection of inter-connected and virtualised computers that are dynamically provisioned and presented as one or more unified computing resources based on service-level agreements (SLA) established through negotiation between the service provider and consumers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id="types-of-cloud-computing"&gt;Types of cloud computing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://imgur.com/J6bx3i3"&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/J6bx3i3.png" title="source: imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SaaS&lt;/strong&gt; (Software as a service ): Self- service with zero operations. Software with no installation, no patch, and operations.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;IaaS&lt;/strong&gt; (Infrastructure as a service ): Agile, on-demand infrastructure. Get things based on your business needs. Very flexible.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;PaaS&lt;/strong&gt; (Application as a service): Application-centric with integrated runtime. Building an application stack is not required.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;CaaS&lt;/strong&gt; (Container as a service): Intelligent machinery for diverse workloads. This machinery helps developers handle all types of workloads. It might not be suitable for other environments, though. Ex:- Kubernetes.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;FaaS&lt;/strong&gt; (Function as a service): Pay-per-use code used for execution only. It is used when something is running as it also makes development fast and easy. ( serverless computing ) &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://imgur.com/EWQ1Fu9"&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/EWQ1Fu9.png" title="source: imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell cloud computing is an SLA between vendor and enterprise, Venders like AWS, Azure.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>