<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title />
		<link>/</link>
		<description />
		<copyright>2021</copyright>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 13:10:35 GMT</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 13:10:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<item>
			<title>Serverless Frameworks</title>
			<link>/posts/serverlessframeworks</link>
			<description>10 January 2021</description>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">/posts/serverlessframeworks</guid>
			<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 18:35:12 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>&lt;h1 id="serverless-frameworks"&gt;Serverless Frameworks.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;serverless frameworks that can work on any major service cloud provider like Amazon, azure, Cloudflare etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amplify Framework&lt;/strong&gt; :- &lt;a href="https://docs.amplify.aws/"&gt;Amzon Amplify&lt;/a&gt;  lib’s, tools and components for AWS-powered cloud apps in serverless specifically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spring Cloud Function&lt;/strong&gt;:-  &lt;a href="https://spring.io/projects/spring-cloud-function"&gt;spring framework&lt;/a&gt; with function friendly  adapters for different clouds dynamic compilation of functions and mechanisms for invoking them for HTTP and messaging source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Claudia js&lt;/strong&gt;:- &lt;a href="https://www.claudiajs.com/"&gt;Claudiajs&lt;/a&gt;  nodejs projects  it automates some key things for deployment and configuration of the API gateway specifically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rubyonjets&lt;/strong&gt;:- &lt;a href="https://rubyonjets.com/"&gt;Rubyonjets&lt;/a&gt;  is for building serverless with ruby language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stackery&lt;/strong&gt;:-  &lt;a href="https://www.stackery.io/"&gt;Stackery&lt;/a&gt; for operational management like building, deployment of systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iopipe&lt;/strong&gt;:-  &lt;a href="https://www.iopipe.com/"&gt;Iopipe&lt;/a&gt; used to building operating functions helps with development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sigma IDE&lt;/strong&gt;:- &lt;a href="https://www.slappforge.com/sigma"&gt;Slappforge&lt;/a&gt; used for building serverless systems and managing serverless systems, with graphical way to build it things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there are many many frameworks out there that support serverless technology, In fact, every popular web programming language as some sort of open-source framework.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
			<comments xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</comments>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What is FaaS</title>
			<link>/posts/faas</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">/posts/faas</guid>
			<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>&lt;h1 id="what-is-serverless-cloud-computing"&gt;What is serverless cloud computing ?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In simple terms serverless computing is bit sided code, unit of discrete components which does one thing in one fine life span. All the responsibilities are delegated to the service provider. Like amazon aws and microsoft azure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responsibilities like choosing an operating system, Capacity management and planning, scaling and reliability of the server anything that breaks this responsibility by the vendor is not fully serverless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are only responsible for maintaining the code.  Developer is no longer involved in hosting the web-app/code online ( server/cloud) no Need to maintain the computing resources like Server, RAM, CPU or any hardware infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;,  let's talk about Azure function or AWS Lambda. As developers, we no longer have to think about which OS or language to use, deployment, and scaling with fault tolerance, logs, updates, metrics, etc. All of this is taken care of by the vendor. In this case, Microsoft or Amazon. We simply outsource these responsibilities to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;According to wikipedia&lt;/strong&gt;  Serverless computing is a cloud computing execution model in which the cloud provider allocates machine resources on demand, taking care of the servers on behalf of the their customers.
Pricing is based on the actual amount of resources consumed by an application , However developers of serverless applications are not concerned with capacity planning, configuration, management, maintenance, operating or scaling of containers, VMs, or physical servers.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id="which-vendors-are-providing-serverless-cloud-computing"&gt;Which vendors are providing serverless cloud computing?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="aws-lambda"&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/"&gt;AWS Lambda&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://imgur.com/DnUvQLc"&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/DnUvQLc.png" title="source: imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;supported languages&lt;/em&gt; node, &lt;strong&gt;java, C#, python&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a href="https://learn.lytics.com/documentation/product/integrations/aws/aws-kinesis/kinesis-triggers"&gt;Triggers kinesis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/dynamodb/"&gt;Amazon DynamoDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/sqs/"&gt;SQS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/serverless-application-model/latest/developerguide/sam-property-function-s3.html"&gt;Amazon S3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/building-serverless-pipelines-with-amazon-cloudwatch-events/"&gt;CloudWatch&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/serverless-application-model/latest/developerguide/sam-property-function-cognito.html"&gt;Cognito&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/config/latest/developerguide/WhatIsConfig.html"&gt;Config&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/lex/"&gt;lex&lt;/a&gt;. Known features dynamic scaling, Cross AZ, Custom runtimes, HTTP via API GateWay, Workflow with step functions, Extensible layers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id="azure-functions"&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-functions/"&gt;Azure functions&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://imgur.com/YCXUF2s"&gt;&lt;img src="https://imgur.com/YCXUF2s.png" title="source: imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;supported languages&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;C#, F#, Java, Node&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-functions/functions-bindings-storage-blob-trigger?tabs=csharp"&gt;Azure Triggers Blob&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/cosmos-db/"&gt;Azure Cosmos DB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/event-grid/"&gt;Azure Event Grid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/event-hubs/"&gt;Azure Event Hubs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-functions/functions-bindings-http-webhook-trigger?tabs=csharp"&gt;Azure HTTP triggers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/service-bus/"&gt;Azure Service Bus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-functions/functions-bindings-timer?tabs=csharp"&gt;Time Triggers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id="google-cloud"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/serverless/"&gt;Google Cloud&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://imgur.com/4UkBSLd"&gt;&lt;img src="https://imgur.com/4UkBSLd.png" title="source: imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Supported Languages&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Node, python, GO&lt;/strong&gt; Available &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/functions/docs/calling/http"&gt;triggers&lt;/a&gt; HTTP, &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/pubsub/"&gt;pub/sub&lt;/a&gt;, Storage, &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/firestore/"&gt;FireStore&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://firebase.google.com/"&gt;Firebase&lt;/a&gt;, Scheduler Features to know Auto Scaled with “max” option,  Version draining,  Function can run under unique identities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id="cloudflare"&gt;Cloudflare&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supported languages &lt;strong&gt;Javascript, webassembly&lt;/strong&gt; Available triggers HTTP Features to know Deploy to 160+ edge data centers, Respond in milliseconds, Workers kv for close data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id="installable-faas"&gt;Installable FaaS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your enterprise can effort a data center then consider this  opens source FaaS platforms  Knative, Apache openwhisk, Kubeless, Pivotal function service, IBM cloud private, GitLab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="how-much-does-it-cost-do-you-need-serverless"&gt;How much does it cost? Do you need serverless?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost estimation for your serverless function add in the requirement and it will estimate a cost for you.
&lt;a href="http://serverlesscalc.com"&gt;serverlesscalc.com&lt;/a&gt;, If you think you need a serverless services? Should your webapp should be a serverless? Then you can check that with the below link. &lt;a href="https://servers.lol"&gt;servers.lol&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
			<comments xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</comments>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What is Cloud Computing</title>
			<link>/posts/cloudcomputing</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">/posts/cloudcomputing</guid>
			<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>&lt;h1 id="what-is-cloud-computing"&gt;What is cloud computing?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell cloud computing allows access to a large amount of computing power in a fully virtualized manner. The aim of this technology is to deliver computing as a utility.
Utility computing is a business model of on-demand delivery of computing power ( pay-as-you-go).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud computing provides multiple services initially offered by microsoft, google and amazon based on a model where computing infrastructure is viewed as a “cloud”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principle of cloud computing behind this model is to offer computing, storage and software as service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Dr. Rajkumar Buyya's Cyberhome says “Cloud is a parallel and distributed computing system consisting of a collection of inter-connected and virtualised computers that are dynamically provisioned and presented as one or more unified computing resources based on service-level agreements (SLA) established through negotiation between the service provider and consumers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id="types-of-cloud-computing"&gt;Types of cloud computing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://imgur.com/2ioC9U8"&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/2ioC9U8.png" title="source: imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SaaS&lt;/strong&gt; (Software as a service ): Self- service with zero operations. Software with no installation, no patch, and operations.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;IaaS&lt;/strong&gt; (Infrastructure as a service ): Agile, on-demand infrastructure. Get things based on your business needs. Very flexible.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;PaaS&lt;/strong&gt; (Application as a service): Application-centric with integrated runtime. Building an application stack is not required.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;CaaS&lt;/strong&gt; (Container as a service): Intelligent machinery for diverse workloads. This machinery helps developers handle all types of workloads. It might not be suitable for other environments, though. Ex:- Kubernetes.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;FaaS&lt;/strong&gt; (Function as a service): Pay-per-use code used for execution only. It is used when something is running as it also makes development fast and easy. ( serverless computing ) &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://imgur.com/wyvifCD"&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/wyvifCD.png" title="source: imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell cloud computing is an SLA between vendor and enterprise, Venders like AWS, Azure.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
			<comments xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>